Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم الإدارة، شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
=Phoenix's Homecoming=
=عودة فينيكس إلى الوطن=
=Episode 20=
=الحلقة 20=
Traitor!
خائن!
- Kill him! - Conspiring with the enemy!
- اقتله! - يتآمر مع العدو!
- Death is too good for him! - Traitor!
الموت رحمة كبيرة له! - خائن!
- Treacherous minister!
- وزير غادر!
- That dog of a Chancellor! - Traitor!
- يا له من مستشار حقير! - خائن!
I am the true ruler!
أنا الحاكم الحقيقي!
How dare you not kneel?
كيف تجرؤ على عدم الركوع؟
Kill him!
اقتله!
Kill the traitor!
اقتلوا الخائن!
Traitor!
خائن!
Kill him!
اقتله!
I regret...
يؤسفني...
I hate...
أكره...
Why didn't I
لماذا لم أفعل
just run you through with my sword?
هل سأطعنك بسيفي؟
Then the throne
ثم العرش
would have belonged to the Huo family.
كانت ستنتمي إلى عائلة هوو.
You once said,
قلتَ ذات مرة،
"Hunting boars requires three-edged arrows."
"صيد الخنازير البرية يتطلب سهامًا ثلاثية الحواف."
The pupil has surpassed the master.
لقد تفوق التلميذ على أستاذه.
I learned well.
لقد تعلمت جيداً.
Even if I die,
حتى لو متُّ،
my soul will endure.
ستبقى روحي خالدة.
Even if I go to the underworld,
حتى لو ذهبت إلى العالم السفلي،
I will see,
سأرى،
Chen Yu,
تشين يو,
how you ruin this empire.
كيف تدمر هذه الإمبراطورية؟
This final game,
هذه المباراة النهائية،
you've lost to me.
لقد خسرت أمامي.
Do you know
هل تعلم
the most exquisite part
الجزء الأكثر روعة
is that the wolf cub you raised
هل هذا هو جرو الذئب الذي قمت بتربيته؟
is now gnawing
يقضم الآن
on the last bone.
على العظمة الأخيرة.
My son,
ابني،
today is your grandfather's...
اليوم هو عيد ميلاد جدك...
No.
لا.
Today is the day traitor Huo Chengxuan meets his fate.
اليوم هو اليوم الذي يلقى فيه الخائن هوو تشنغشوان مصيره.
Your Highness, the Chancellor...
صاحب السمو، المستشار...
Father,
أب،
when teaching me chess, you told me
عندما علمتني الشطرنج، أخبرتني
to sacrifice pieces quickly
التضحية بالأجزاء بسرعة
and ruthlessly.
وبلا رحمة.
Did it ever cross your mind
هل خطر ذلك ببالك من قبل؟
that one day,
في ذلك اليوم،
the biggest sacrificial piece
أكبر قطعة تضحية
would be you?
هل ستكون أنت؟
My son,
ابني،
remember this day.
تذكر هذا اليوم.
The deadliest move in the world
أخطر خطوة في العالم
is family.
هي عائلة.
Everyone,
الجميع،
the Grand Princess was wronged.
لقد تعرضت الأميرة الكبرى للظلم.
Luckily, His Majesty uncovered the truth.
لحسن الحظ، كشف جلالته الحقيقة.
The traitor stands condemned.
الخائن مدان.
As a scion of the Sheng family,
بصفته سليل عائلة شينغ،
by imperial decree,
بموجب مرسوم إمبراطوري،
I proclaim the charges.
أعلن التهم الموجهة.
Proclaim the charges.
أعلنوا التهم.
Traitor Huo Chengxuan
الخائن هوو تشينغ شوان
showed no respect to heaven,
لم يُظهر أي احترام للسماء،
and slaughtered common folk below.
وقاموا بذبح عامة الناس في الأسفل.
Holding high office,
شغل منصباً رفيعاً،
he should have served his sovereign loyally.
كان ينبغي عليه أن يخدم سيده بإخلاص.
Yet he was consumed by desire, committing grave crimes.
لكنه كان مستهلكاً بالرغبة، فارتكب جرائم خطيرة.
In the third year of Jiahe,
في السنة الثالثة من جياخه،
driven by personal ambition, he forged evidence,
بدافع من طموحه الشخصي، قام بتزوير الأدلة.
leading to the wrongful death of the Grand Princess.
مما أدى إلى وفاة الأميرة الكبرى ظلماً .
First kowtow!
أول انحناءة!
Plead for the Grand Princess!
ناشدوا من أجل الأميرة الكبرى!
Kill him!
اقتله!
Traitor!
خائن!
Treacherous minister!
وزير خائن!
Kill him!
اقتله!
Traitor Huo Chengxuan
الخائن هوو تشينغ شوان
- Kill him! - colluded with foreign enemies,
- اقتلوه! - تواطأ مع أعداء أجانب،
causing the loyal soldiers of the Sheng army
مما تسبب في توتر صفوف جنود جيش شينغ المخلصين
to die unjustly at the border.
أن يموت ظلماً على الحدود.
Their bones lie cold, barely buried!
عظامهم ملقاة باردة، بالكاد مدفونة!
Plead for the loyal martyrs
ناشدوا من أجل الشهداء الأوفياء
of the Sheng family.
من عائلة شينغ.
Second kowtow!
السجود الثاني!
Plead for the loyal martyrs of the Sheng family!
نناشد من أجل شهداء عائلة شينغ المخلصين!
Indeed.
بالفعل.
He's too evil to die just once.
إنه شرير للغاية لدرجة أنه لا يمكن أن يموت مرة واحدة فقط.
This is
هذا هو
the battle standard stained
راية المعركة ملطخة
with the blood of 30,000 Sheng soldiers!
بدماء 30 ألف جندي من جنود شينغ!
Here is the secret letter you wrote,
هذه هي الرسالة السرية التي كتبتها،
demanding King Liang send troops
يطالب الملك ليانغ بإرسال قوات
to lure the Sheng army into a trap
لجذب جيش شينغ إلى فخ
and massacre them all!
واذبحهم جميعاً!
His crimes demand death!
جرائمه تستحق الموت!
Now,
الآن،
Chancellor Huo's crimes are exposed to all.
جرائم المستشار هوو مكشوفة للجميع.
He shall be punished
سيُعاقب
to appease the people
لتهدئة الشعب
and to honor the loyal souls.
وتكريماً للأرواح المخلصة.
Three bows!
ثلاثة انحناءات!
Plead for the people's suffering!
ناشدوا من أجل معاناة الشعب!
His Majesty has arrived.
لقد وصل جلالته.
(In Memory of Grand Princess, Sheng Yunlin)
(في ذكرى الأميرة الكبرى، شينغ يونلين)
Kneel properly!
اركع بشكل صحيح!
Welcome the tablet of Grand Princess, Sheng Yunlin.
أهلاً بكم في لوحة الأميرة الكبرى، شينغ يونلين.
Do it.
افعلها.
Heaven has no eyes!
السماء بلا عيون!
Back then, Chancellor Huo
في ذلك الوقت، المستشار هو
colluded with the enemy state,
تواطأ مع الدولة المعادية،
causing thousands of Sheng men to shed blood on the battlefield
مما تسبب في إراقة دماء الآلاف من رجال شينغ في ساحة المعركة
and die a dishonest death.
ويموت ميتة غير شريفة.
He branded me a traitorous collaborator.
لقد وصفني بالمتعاون الخائن.
Then he sent Su Wei to kill in my Weiyang Palace.
ثم أرسل سو وي ليقتل في قصر وييانغ الخاص بي.
He ordered Huo Wan to burn the evidence.
أمر هوو وان بحرق الأدلة.
He schemed against me so thoroughly,
لقد دبر مكيدة ضدي بشكل محكم للغاية،
but did he ever consider
لكن هل فكر في الأمر يوماً؟
that today he'd be outmaneuvered to death.
أنه سيُهزم اليوم ويُقتل.
The Sheng men were all loyal and brave.
كان رجال شينغ جميعهم مخلصين وشجعان.
After so many years,
بعد كل هذه السنوات،
their names are finally cleared.
تمت تبرئة أسمائهم أخيراً.
Their unwavering devotion was not in vain.
لم يذهب إخلاصهم الراسخ سدى.
Lord Xie,
اللورد شي،
aren't you usually the epitome of composure?
ألا تُعتبر عادةً مثالاً للهدوء والاتزان؟
Why are you so visibly elated today?
لماذا تبدو سعيداً للغاية اليوم؟
I've discussed with Mother.
لقد تحدثت مع أمي.
Once all matters are settled,
بمجرد تسوية جميع الأمور،
I will prepare all necessary rites,
سأقوم بإعداد جميع الطقوس اللازمة،
and request you from the Sheng family.
وأطلب منكم من عائلة شينغ.
Then,
ثم،
with a proper, honorable wedding,
بحفل زفاف لائق ومحترم،
I will bring you into my home.
سأدخلك إلى منزلي.
I won't betray you.
لن أخونك.
Rushing to marry in such a fluster?
هل من الحكمة التسرع في الزواج في مثل هذه الحالة من الارتباك؟
Aren't you ashamed?
ألا تشعر بالخجل؟
I want everyone under heaven to know
أريد أن يعلم كل من تحت السماء
that you are my wife.
أنكِ زوجتي.
(Huo Wan)
(هو وان)
Xie the ice block,
شيه كتلة الثلج،
why so many vats in your house?
لماذا يوجد كل هذا العدد من الأحواض في منزلك؟
Huaiyong isn't home.
هوايونغ ليس في المنزل.
Do I not exist to you?
ألا وجود لي بالنسبة لك؟
My lady!
سيدتي!
You're finally back!
لقد عدت أخيراً!
I've waited so bitterly.
لقد انتظرت بفارغ الصبر.
You climb over walls every day.
أنت تتسلق الجدران كل يوم.
Lady Xie provides you with fine meals.
تقدم لكم السيدة شي وجبات شهية.
Where's the bitterness?
أين المرارة؟
My lady, you have no idea.
سيدتي، ليس لديكِ أدنى فكرة.
God knows
الله أعلم
where Xie Fei got all those vats again
من أين حصل شيه فاي على كل تلك الخزانات مرة أخرى؟
and placed them by the wall.
ووضعوها بجانب الجدار.
I thought there won't be
ظننت أنه لن يكون هناك
any vats after I smashed them last time.
أي خزانات بعد أن حطمتها في المرة الماضية.
Get away!
ابتعد!
Didn't stop you, the wall-scaling thief.
لم يوقفك ذلك أيها اللص الذي يتسلق الجدران.
I truly don't know
لا أعرف حقاً
what's so great about Xie the ice block.
ما المميز في شيه، كتلة الجليد؟
He's born a workhorse.
لقد وُلد ليكون حصان عمل.
My lady,
سيدتي،
- why not come with me? - I...
- لماذا لا تأتي معي؟ - أنا...
I heard
سمعت
a new opera troupe came to the southern city,
وصلت فرقة أوبرا جديدة إلى المدينة الجنوبية،
by the temple fair.
بجوار معرض المعبد.
Let's go have fun together.
هيا بنا نستمتع معاً.
You've now
لقد أصبحت الآن
gotten so familiar with the capital.
أصبحتُ على دراية كبيرة بالعاصمة.
My lady,
سيدتي،
look up at the sky.
انظر إلى السماء.
Don't you want to see
ألا تريد أن ترى
what this land you fought for will become?
ماذا ستؤول إليه هذه الأرض التي قاتلت من أجلها؟
What Xie Fei can give you,
ما يمكن أن يقدمه لك شي فاي،
I can give you too.
يمكنني أن أعطيك أيضاً.
What he cannot give you,
ما لا يستطيع أن يمنحك إياه،
I also can.
وأنا أيضاً أستطيع.
Are you willing
هل أنت مستعد؟
to be confined within this small grid,
أن يكون محصوراً ضمن هذه الشبكة الصغيرة،
within the imperial city,
داخل المدينة الإمبراطورية،
as some fated lady?
كإحدى السيدات اللاتي قُدِّر لهن ذلك؟
I am not willing.
أنا غير راغب.
But Li Jingche,
لكن لي جينغتشي،
in this life,
في هذه الحياة،
I will marry only Xie Fei.
لن أتزوج إلا شي فاي.
Miss Sheng,
الآنسة شينغ،
it is the palace's decree summoning you.
هذا مرسوم القصر الذي يستدعيك.
(For Sheng Yunlin Only)
(خاص بشركة شينغ يونلين فقط)
♪The wind rises, snow falls♪
♪تهب الرياح، ويتساقط الثلج♪
♪To stain endless remorse with red♪
♪لتلطيخ الندم الذي لا ينتهي باللون الأحمر♪
♪No regrets in moves made. Let the game unfold♪
لا ندم على الخطوات التي اتخذتها. دع اللعبة تتكشف.
♪Sorrow and joy intertwined♪
♪الحزن والفرح متشابكان♪
♪Yet we can't escape karma♪
♪لكننا لا نستطيع الهروب من الكارما♪
♪Lament this fleeting life♪
♪رثوا هذه الحياة الزائلة♪
♪So elusive♪
♪مراوغ للغاية♪
♪So indistinct♪
♪غير واضح للغاية♪
♪Resent farewells♪
♪وداعات حزينة♪
♪Remembering each other♪
♪نتذكر بعضنا البعض♪
♪Love can't be extinguished♪
♪الحب لا ينطفئ♪
♪Unwilling to accept♪
♪غير راغب في القبول♪
♪Rewriting the story♪
♪إعادة كتابة القصة♪
♪And praying♪
♪والصلاة♪
♪A long-cherished wish♪
أمنية طالما تمنيتها
♪In a daze♪
♪في حالة ذهول♪
♪Suddenly it's those years again♪
♪فجأة تعود تلك السنوات من جديد♪
♪How I wish to relive my old dreams♪
♪كم أتمنى أن أعيش أحلامي القديمة من جديد♪
♪Rewrite those torn pages♪
♪أعد كتابة تلك الصفحات الممزقة♪